Distant Thunder
Shanyang Castle
One day,
（ナレーター）
ある日のこと
the State of Qin units that had successfully subjugated the Shanyang region
山陽(さんよう)一帯の
平定に成功した秦国(しんこく)軍の主たる部隊
そして 占領後の
山陽の施政に当たっていた文官たち
and the government officials of the now-occupied Shanyang
その一同が山陽城に集められた
were both gathered at Shanyang Castle.
Geez, why'd they bring us all to a place like this? It's sweltering.
（信(しん)）チッ！ 何なんだよ？
こんな所に集めやがって
暑苦しい！
（渕(えん)）山陽を平定したから
その ねぎらいでしょう
We did subjugate Shanyang, we should be appreciative of that much.
But for even their civil officials to be here is a little odd.
（貂(てん)）でも
文官まで いるのは ちょっと変だな
（じい）蒙恬(もうてん)さま
Lord Meng Tian, have you heard anything?
何か聞いておられますか？
（蒙恬）何も
Nothing.
（兵士Ｂ）あっ！ ぎょ… 玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊だ
（どよめき）
It-It's the Yufeng Unit.
The unit sent to subjugate Shanggui?
（兵士Ａ）
上圭(じょうけい)を平定しに出ていった玉鳳隊
戻ってきたのか！
They're back?!
（兵士Ｃ）
あれが隊長の千人将 王賁(おうほん)だ！
That's their captain, the Thousand-Man General Wang Ben!
（信）ヘッ… あの野郎 やっと
持ち場を平定してきやがったのか
So that bastard finally subjugated his position, eh?
Man, they're slow!
遅(おっせ)えなぁ ハハハハッ！
No, they're not!
そうじゃない！
（信）えっ？
I'm pretty sure the Yufeng Unit has been quickly taking down enemy positions.
確か 玉鳳隊は
早々に持ち場の敵を討って
Yufeng Unit
Yuehua Unit
Feixin Unit
３つも場所を変えながら
平定して回ってたんだ
So much so that they went through three different areas and subjugated them all.
なに？
What?
Who're those all-black guys?
（信）何だ？ あの黒ずくめどもは
あっ あれは まさか…
（信）うん？
Could those guys be...?
蒙恬さま あれは確か…
（蒙恬）ああ 大本営
Lord Meng Tian...
Are they...?
Yes. The imperial headquarters.
秦国朝廷直属の特殊護衛部隊
The special guard unit directly under control by the State of Qin Imperial Court.
つまり 政府の要人が
派遣されてきたってことだ
In other words, important government members have been dispatched here.
Th-Those are...
あっ！ あれは…
（ざわめき）
Chanpingjun and... Li Si!
昌平君(しょうへいくん)に李斯(りし)！
（兵士）えっ？ 軍総司令？
The army Commander-in-Chief?!
Why is the Commander-in-Chief out on the front lines?
（兵士）
えっ？ 総司令が こんな前線に？
Master?!
先生…
And behind Master is the head of the administration, Li Si?
先生の後ろには 行政の長(おさ)の李斯か
なにかイヤな予感…
I've got a bad feeling about this...
Two of Lü Shi's Four Pillars are here, at Shanyang?
（王賁）呂氏(りょし)四柱のうち２人が
ここ山陽に？
I will now be announcing our nation's plan for this land of Shanyang.
（昌平君）これより―
ここ山陽についての
国の方針を発表する
（昌平君）今日この時をもって―
From this moment,
Shanyang's name will now be changed to Dongjun, eastern commandery of the State of Qin.
山陽は 秦国の東郡(とうぐん)という名称に
変わるものとする
Along with that, we will be migrating 10,000 people of the State of Qin here.
それに伴い
秦国人１万を移住させる
移住？ １万？
Migrating?! 10,000?!
Regarding the government, it will be under the rule of our head of government administration, Li Si,
（昌平君）政治においては
行政の長 李斯のもと―
and the land will be under State of Qin law.
秦国の法のもとに この地を治める
元からの住民であっても
承知しかねる者は即座に強制退去だ
Even for the original citizens of this land, those that do not consent to these laws will be deported immediately.
So it's happened, huh?
来たか…
So starting now, each of you must burn into your minds the idea that this place,
よって 今より ここ東郡は―
Dongjun, is State of Qin soil which we must risk our lives to protect!
我らが命を賭して守るべき
秦国の国土そのものとなった旨
各自 頭に焼き付けよ！
私からは以上だ
That is all.
Wh-What the hell?
なっ… これって 一体…
決意表明だよ
（信）決意表明？
It's an expression of determination.
Expression of determination?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）この時代は 各国が
国土の奪い合いに終始していた
In this era, the kingdoms constantly
take land from one another.
The usual state of things is that taken land quickly gets taken back again.
奪った地は また
すぐに奪われるというのが常である
その地に住民を移住させ
“郡”とする異例の行為は―
The exceptional tactic of emigrating citizens to that land and making it a commandery
この地を絶対に手放さないという
強い意志の表れであり
indicated a strong will not to let go of this land.
また
これを国策としたということは―
As well as an indicator that this would be a national policy for the next time as well.
“次もある”ということである
つまり 始皇(しこう)５年の
この山陽東郡宣言というのは―
In other words, the Shi Huang Year 5 Shanyang Dongjun Declaration
秦国が
領土拡大に本腰を入れるという―
was a war proclamation to other kingdoms that the State of Qin was about to set about expanding its territory in earnest.
諸国に対しての
宣戦布告だったのである
Shanyang
（李牧(りぼく)）
やはり 始めるしかないか…
We have no choice but to start now, don't we?
Lord Li Mu...
（カイネ）李牧さま…
（李牧）公孫龍(こうそんりゅう)将軍
General Gongsun Long.
軍を起こす準備をしてください
（公孫龍）はっ！
Please begin preparation for mobilizing the troops.
Yes, sir.
Send word to General Wan Ji and Li Bai.
（李牧）
将軍の万極(まんごく)と李白(りはく)にも通達を
We are starting a war on the order of 100,000.
10万規模の戦を始めます
So you're finally breaking the alliance with the State of Qin and starting a war...?
（カイネ）ついに
秦国との同盟を破って 戦争を…
（李牧）
いえ 攻め込むのは燕国(えんこく)です
No. We are attacking the State of Yan.
えっ？ 燕国ですか？
The State of Yan?!
And would you be the Great General, Lord Li Mu?
（公孫龍）
して 大将は李牧さまが？
（李牧）いいえ
No.
I've got to go and awaken that one soon.
そろそろ あの方に
目を覚ましていただきましょう
A bit of time after Shanyang became Dongjun...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）山陽が
東郡と改められて しばらくののち
信たち飛信(ひしん)隊には 別の土地で
新たな任務が与えられていた
Xin and the Feixin Unit were given a new mission in a different region.
Border security for the neighboring State of Chu, a large kingdom which requires constant guard.
隣国であり 常に警戒が必要な
大国 楚(そ)との国境警備であった
Calm down, Xin.
（尾平(びへい)）落ち着けよ 信
This is what doing border security is like.
国境警備の仕事なんて
こんなもんよ
だけどよ 楚の連中には
ホントにイライラさせられるぜ
But those Chu jerks really piss me off.
毎日毎日
チラチラ様子うかがいに来るなら
If you're gonna freakin' come see how things are every day,
then at least launch a damn attack!
とっとと攻めてこいってんだ！
（尾平）だから 気持ちは…
Like I told you, I understand how you feel, but—
（渕）大変です！
Big trouble!
What's wrong, Mr. Yuan?!
どうした？ 渕さん
どっかで楚が動いたのか？
Is Chu on the move somewhere?
（渕）信どの こんな時期に楚が
攻めてくることなんかありません
Lord Xin, Chu would not be attacking at a time like this!
Then what's this about?!
だったら 何が大変なんだよ？
Pang Nuan has emerged!
龐煖(ほうけん)が出てきたんですよ！
えっ？ なんだと！
What?!
（信）
龐煖が総大将で出てきただと？
Pang Nuan has appeared as a Supreme Commander?!
Yes, no doubt about it.
（貂）ああ 間違いない
馬陽(ばよう)のときと同じで 大将が龐煖
Just like at Mayang, the Great General is Pang Nuan.
実際
その後ろで軍を動かすのは 李牧
But the one actually operating that army behind the scenes is Li Mu.
兵は10万以上
既に 燕国の軍と接触したみたいだ
There are over 100,000 soldiers.
It looks like they made contact with the State of Yan first.
（尾平）じゅ… 10万！
100,000?!
Pang Nuan...
（信）龐煖…
( Flag - Yan )
（貂）燕国も規模は同じだ
10万をそろえた
The State of Yan's army is the same size. 100,000.
（信）
10万と10万の戦いかよ…
So it's a battle of 100,000 VS 100,000?
Sounds like an incredible war right off the bat.
いきなり すごい戦を
始めやがったもんだな
State of Zhao Three Great Devas Pang Nuan
（貂）秦国が 魏国(ぎこく)の
山陽を攻めたように
Just like how the State of Qin attacked the State of Wei,
while the State of Zhao has an alliance with us,
趙国(ちょうこく)も
同盟が生きているうちに
they intend to take down the enemies behind them.
背後の仇敵(きゅうてき)を
討っておくつもりだろう
（信）
そうか… もともと 秦趙同盟は―
I see...
I remember Li Mu saying that the purpose of the Qin-Zhao Alliance was so they could focus on the State of Zhao.
燕国との戦いに集中するためとか
李牧も言ってたな
Hey, Diao.
おい 貂
燕って 一体 どんな国なんだ？
Just what sorta kingdom is Yan?
There are a lot of mysteries about that place.
燕国は謎が多いんだ
Zhao
Zhong Mountains
Yan
東の端にあって 秦国からは遠い
この数十年 戦った記録もない
It's very far from the State of Qin, in the East.
There are no records of us fighting with them in the past several decades.
どういう武将がいるかも
分かってない
We don't know what sort of military commanders they have either.
But they have one Great General whom is known throughout all of China.
でも １人だけ 中華全土に
名を知らしめてる大将軍がいる
なに！ 何て名だ？ その将軍は
What?
Who is that?!
Ju Xin.
劇辛(げきしん)
40 years ago when the State of Yan had been cornered by the State of Qi,
40年前
斉国(せいこく)に燕国が追い詰められたとき
together with the now deceased Army God Yue Yi,
今は亡き軍神 楽毅(がくき)と２人―
they pushed back against the State of Qi to the point where they were near collapse.
逆に 斉国を
滅亡寸前まで押し返したんだ
There's an awesome general like that around?
そんな すげえ将軍がいたのか…
（貂）ああ
Yeah.
もともとは趙国にいたんだ
He's originally from the State of Zhao.
そのまま趙国にとどまっていれば
They say that if he had stayed in the State of Zhao,
廉頗(れんぱ)の時代の三大天に
なっていたともいわれている
he would've became one of the
Great Devas from Lian Po's era.
The Great Devas of Lian Po's era...
廉頗の時代の三大天…
しかし 趙国も李牧と龐煖だぞ
But the State of Zhao has Li Mu and Pang Nuan...
That war's gonna be a real close one.
その戦 もつれに もつれるな
（信）そうだな
Yeah.
どっちが勝つにせよ
簡単に決着は つかねえだろう
Whichever one wins, it's not gonna be an easy victory.
突然もたらされた趙国と燕国の
大規模な戦の知らせ
Suddenly, news had come of a large-scale war between the State of Zhao and the State of Yan.
それは信の心を大きく震わせた
That truly shook Xin's heart.
But with them stuck there vacantly glaring at the State of Chu's army,
だが 楚国の軍とは むなしく
にらみ合いが続くばかりで
three days passed.
Xin
それから３日が過ぎた
そ… その話は本当なのか？
I-Is that true?
（貂）ついさっき ようやく
ここにも報告が入ったんだ
The report just finally reached us a minute ago.
趙国と燕国の戦 決着がついた
The war between the State of Zhao and the State of Yan is over.
なんだと？ 10万と10万の戦が
何日もたたねえで…
What?
That war of 100,000 VS 100,000 only lasted a few days...
Not even that!
（貂）それどころじゃない！
It was just one day!
たった１日だ…
たった１日で決着がついたんだ
The war ended in just one day!
How... did it happen?
どう決着がついたんだ？
（貂）李牧の策略で 最初のうちは
燕国の軍も翻弄されるばかりだった
With Li Mu's strategy, the State of Yan Army was just being toyed with at first.
But then Great General Ju Xin proved his reputation.
でも さすがは大将軍の劇辛だ
He saw through Li Mu's strategy and launched a counterattack.
そんな李牧の策略を見破って
反撃に出た
だけど 趙国には あの龐煖がいた
But the State of Zhao had Pang Nuan.
State of Yan General Ju Xin
（趙兵たち）ウワッ…
ハッ… か… 片腕で！
O-One handed?!
（信）最後は大将同士の一騎打ちか
So it ended with a one-on-one battle between Great Generals?
So Pang Nuan took out State of Yan Great General Ju Xin?
それで
龐煖が燕国の大将軍 劇辛を…
Just how much of a monster is that guy?
あいつ どこまでバケモノなんだ…
Li Mu finally defeated the State of Yan just like he wanted.
李牧は とうとう
念願だった燕国をたたいた
So of course, he's not going to just stop
当然 このままじゃ終わらない
次は秦国ってことか
（貂）そうだ
So you're saying the State of Qin is next, right?
That's right.
The alliance is still active,
まだ同盟は生きているけど
趙国の動きは活発になっている
but the State of Zhao's actions are becoming vigorous.
And there are signs of the State of Chu moving as well.
楚の国も動く気配がある
だから こうして
国境警備を命じられているわけだし
That's why we were ordered on border security here.
Something truly... truly bad might happen.
本当に… 本当に大変なことが
起こるのかもしれない
You mean a war with Chu?
（信）楚とも戦になるのか？
すぐじゃないと思うけど…
I don't think it'll be soon...
Chu is an enormous kingdom.
楚は超大国だ
国土は楚１国で ６国を
足し合わせたほどの広大な国だ
In terms of land area, Chu is as big as six other states.
Six kingdoms in one?!
（尾平）
１国で６国！ そんなにか…
It's that big?!
（貂）正直 軍力の規模は
どれほどのものなのか―
To be honest, I can't even imagine how large their army is.
想像もできないくらいだ
（信）えっ？ おかしいじゃねえか
That's kinda weird, ain't it?
そんなに強(つえ)えんなら
なんで攻め入ってこねえんだよ？
If they're that strong, then why don't they attack us?
That's because their size can actually be an encumbrance.
それは 広大さが
逆に枷(かせ)にもなっているからだ
Qi
Zhao
Wei
Han
Chu
Qin
Because Chu is so wide, it borders Qin, Han, Wei, Zhao, and Qi.
楚は横に広いせいで
秦 韓(かん) 魏 趙 斉の
A national border of 5 different kingdoms.
実に５か国と
広く国境をなしている
だから 他国への侵攻に
Therefore it has to be careful about attacking other nations.
慎重に
ならざるをえないんだ
攻めに出れば
Because if they launch an attack, they may be attacked by other kingdoms.
ほかの国に
攻め込まれるから
なるほど… でかいと
身軽には動けねえってことか
I get it.
They're so big that they can't be too casual about when they move.
Be that as it may, it's said that once they do get moving they always have enough power to crush an entire kingdom.
とはいっても いざ始まれば―
１国をたたきつぶす力は
常に備えているという話だ
That's why every state tries to avoid any direct conflicts with Chu.
だから どの国も いきなり楚と
まともに戦うことは避けてきた
But then we wouldn't fight Chu no matter how much time passed, right?
だけど それじゃ いつまでたっても
楚とは戦えねえじゃねえかよ
（貂）
それは違う　秦国軍の本営は―
That's not so.
The State of Qin's headquarters is steadily drawing out a map and developing a strategy for a large-scale war on Chu.
着々と楚との大戦の設計図を描いて
戦略を練っている
山陽の東郡宣言も
それが進んできてる証拠だ
The Shanyang Dongjun Declaration was a sign that those plans are progressing.
For real?
（尾平）ホントかよ？
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
だが 楚の軍に目立った動きもなく
But the Chu Army did not make any conspicuous movements
信たちの部隊に
新たな命令も下されなかった
and no new orders were handed down to Xin's unit.
Look.
（兵士Ｂ）オッ… 見ろ
（兵士Ａ）うん？
オオッ！ やっと交代
Oh, shift's finally done.
ウ～ン…
ウワーッ！
Wh-Why are you sleeping here?!
な… なんで
お前が ここで寝てるんだよ？
し… しかも！ しかも！
And... And...
Huh? Yeah, why was it?
あれ？ どうしてだっけ？
寝ぼけてた？ 悪い…
Did I wander in half awake?
Ah, sorry...
“悪い”じゃねえよ！
You're friggin' sorry?!
（兵士Ｃ）
おはようさんです 貂軍師
Good morning, Strategist Diao.
Good morning.
おはよう
Before I knew it, I had been the strategist of the Feixin Unit for over 3 months.
（貂）早いもんで 俺が飛信隊の
軍師になって もう３か月以上
何だかんだで
俺は うまく なじめた
Somehow or other, I was getting pretty used to it.
俺は女だけど―
It looks like nobody's making weird passes at me even though I'm a woman because I'm Xin's close friend.
誰も変な ちょっかいを
出してこないのは―
信の身内だからってことらしい
（兵士）おう！
なんだ？ てめえ 朝っぱらから
What're you doing at the crack of dawn, bastard?!
（貂）ここの連中は 信に似て
みんな口が悪くて がさつだ
The guys around here are like Xin in that they're foul-mouthed and boorish.
But I'm comfortable being among them.
だけど この中にいるのは 心地いい
Hey, those guys are picking a fight?!
ハァ… バカばっか フフッ…
What a bunch of morons.
Who did what?!
（楚水(そすい)）河了貂(かりょうてん)どの
Lord He Liao Diao.
新しい命令が？
A new order?
はい ようやく
Yes, finally.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
楚との国境警備に就いてから３か月
3 months have passed since the border patrol of Chu began.
飛信隊に新たな命令が下された
Now the Feixin Unit has been given new orders.
The border patrol mission has been canceled
国境警備の任は解かれ
飛信隊は 東の先端の城 東金(とうきん)を
目指すことになった
and the Feixin Unit is now targeting the castle to the far East, Dongjin.
秦国軍が国境を離れると同時に―
The same time the State of Qin Army left the border,
as if it had been arranged, the Chu Army left the border as well.
まるで申し合わせたかのように
楚の軍も国境から離れていった
This isn't good.
（貂）マズイな
（信）どうした？ 貂
What is it, Diao?
This place is already off the map.
この辺りは
もう地図には載ってない
Wha?
For the State of Qin, this is unknown land.
秦国軍にとっては
未開の土地なんだよ
But still, we're on the front lines of an invasion to the East.
それだけ 俺たちは
東への侵攻の最前線にいるってこと
警戒態勢で進もう
We should proceed with caution.
This area has borders to Wei, Zhao, and Chu.
ここ一帯は
魏 趙 楚の国境が入り組んでて
It wouldn't be odd to see any one of them show up.
どこが出てきても おかしくない
了解！
Got it!
All units, proceed with caution!
（兵士）全軍 警戒態勢！
（兵士）警戒態勢で進め！
Move forward with caution!
（兵士）索敵 増やせ！
（兵士）左の茂み 注意しろ！
Increase search for the enemy!
Watch out for the thicket on the left!
クッ…
俺らが外側に就いてるときに！
Just when we were put on the outside...
（慶(けい)）お前が
端っこがいいっつったんだろう！
You said you wanted to go to the edge!
You said the inside was sweltering.
中は暑苦しいって！
Quit it with the side comments.
いきなり横から“ワ～ッ”なんて
やめてくれよ
アアッ！ て… 敵襲？
A-An enemy attack?!
Enemy attack! Enemy attack!
敵襲！ 敵襲だ！
（信）なに！ 尾平の声か？
What?! That's Wei Ping's voice!
H-Hold on, Mr. Wei Ping!
（昂(こう)）
ちょ… ちょっと待って 尾平さん！
Look!
あれ！
（尾平）えっ？
（秀(しゅう)）ハァハァ…
H-Help...
（秀）た… 助けて…
（慶）あっ おい！
（尾平）信を呼べ！
H-Hey! Call Xin over!
Be on guard for enemies!
（兵士）敵の警戒をしろ！
Did you come to?
気づいたか…
ゆっくり飲め
Drink this, slowly.
何があった？
What happened?
徐(じょ)の城が…
Xu... castle... was... attacked by... Han...
韓軍に襲われて…
Han!
（２人）韓…
韓って…
（去亥(きょがい)）戦ったことがねえ国だ
Han?
That's a country we've never fought with before.
徐って分かるか？ 貂
（貂）いや 聞いたことがない
Have you heard of Xu, Diao?
No, never heard of it.
おい それは楚か 魏か 趙か？
どこの城だ？
Hey, whose castle is that? Chu's? Wei's? Zhao's?
ど… どこの城でもありません
It... It wasn't any place's castle...
徐は国です
Xu is... a kingdom.
僕は徐の人間… 徐人 秀です
I'm a person of Xu.
My name is Xiu.
何言ってんだ？
（去亥）そんな国ねえだろうが
What's he talking about?
There's no such kingdom.
いや ちょっと待って
No, hold on a minute.
この中華は
もともと100以上の国に分かれてて
China was once split between over 100 kingdoms
500年かけて
今の７大国に淘汰(とうた)された
and over 500 years, it was reduced to 7 large kingdoms.
でも 実は７国に吸収されず
But I've heard that there are actually small, fragile kingdoms existing in the mountains that weren't absorbed by the 7 states.
山地の中で
か細く残っている小国たちが―
存在してるっていうのは
聞いたことがある
じゃ この近くに
その徐って国があるってことか？
So... that Xu kingdom is nearby?
（秀）た… 助けてください
P-Please, help us...
みんな どんどん殺されて…
Everyone... is being killed one by one...
おっ母を助けて… お願い
Please... help... my mother...
A-Are you sure about acting on our own like this?
（慶）
い… いいのかよ？ こんな勝手に
What about Dongjin Castle?
東金城は どうするんだ？
（田永(でんえい)）いいわけねえだろう
立派な命令違反だ
Of course we're not sure!
This is a real violation of orders!
（側近）副長…
（楚水）分かってる
Vice Captain...
I know.
But this is also one of the good things about Lord Xin.
だが
これが信どのの いい所でもある
しっかり道案内しろよ
Show us exactly where it is.
は… はい
O-Okay.
何か文句あるか？ 貂
Any objections, Diao?
'Course not.
（貂）あるわけないだろう
State of Qin Xiangyang
（ナレーター）
ここで物語は時間を遡り
We will now go back in time a bit in our story and switch the stage to the State of Qin Capital of Xiangyang.
そして 舞台を
秦国の都 咸陽(かんよう)に移す
When the Feixin Unit was focusing solely on the border with Chu,
飛信隊が楚との国境警備に
就いたばかりのころ
there were major movements in Xiangyang.
咸陽では 大きな動きが起きていた
（文官Ａ）
報告します！ 高離(こうり)家 臨(りん)家―
Reporting!
The Gaoli Family and the Lin Family have moved to the Lü Buwei Faction.
共に呂不韋(りょふい)陣営へ翻りました
The Yuezhuo family as well!
（文官Ｂ）楽卓(らくたく)一族も同様です
（文官Ｃ）魚伯(ぎょはく)氏も中立の立場から
丞相(じょうしょう)側へ なびきました
Yubo Shi has also yielded from being neutral to the chancellor's side.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）
う～む… 予測は していたが…
We predicted this, but...
（肆氏(しし)）ここまで急に動くとは…
But for them to move this quickly...
With the rumors of his relationship with the queen dowager
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
太后との関係が取り沙汰され
その勢力を
弱めていた呂不韋の陣営であったが
it was Lü Buwei's camp that lost power.
But coming up to this point, a sudden recoup began.
ここに来て 急激な巻き返しを
始めていたのである
And powerful allies disappeared from Zheng's side one by one.
そして 一方の政(せい)のそばからは―
有力な協力者たちが
次々と離れていった
その陰には
呂不韋の積極的な計略があったのだ
The cause was Lü Buwei's assertive plan.
He sent one man to the queen dowager.
彼は
太后のもとへ ひとりの男を送った
A man the queen dowager was entranced with.
太后が夢中になる男を…
And so, while the scandal between Lü Buwei and the queen dowager continued
こうして 呂不韋は
太后との醜聞をやり過ごしつつも
彼女との関係は ひそかに保ち
his relationship with her was secretly maintained
これまで以上に 後宮陣営との
結び付きを深いものとしたのである
and his relations with the harem camp grew stronger than ever.
Oh, Li Si?
おお 李斯か
（李斯）
私や昌平君が咸陽を離れている間に
I'm honestly surprised that while Changpingjun and I were away from Xiangyang
丞相が
ここまで力を戻されるとは…
you regained this much power, chancellor.
正直 驚いております
（李斯）しかし 後宮の力を
あそこまで取り込んだのは―
But I feel that gaining that much of the harem's power
will be a double-edged sword.
諸刃(もろは)の剣であったと思われますが…
何じゃ？ 黙って動いたことを
怒っておるのか？
What? Upset I made moves without telling you?
そんな稚拙な話ではありません
Nothing so childish.
ハハハハッ！ 許せ許せ
Sorry, sorry.
I only did it out of consideration for you with you being so busy.
わしなりに 多忙を極める そちらに
気を遣ったつもりだった
それに これは
身から出たサビでもあったからのぅ
And... because you've gotten a bit rusty.
Well, now the matter is settled.
まあ よい　これでカタがついた
ここから たまった うっぷん
晴らさせてもらうぞ
I'll be clearing away all of the resentment I've amassed.
Li Si.
李斯よ
（李斯）はっ！
Sir.
わしは丞相を卒業するぞ
I'm graduating from being a chancellor.
Sir?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）それから しばらくして
Some time after that
呂不韋は丞相の地位を超え
相国(しょうこく)という位に就いた
Lü Buwei rose above the rank of chancellor to the position of Prime Minister.
相国とは最高位の席であり
Prime Minister is the highest seat.
The only one higher than this rank is the king.
これを超えるのは
もはや国王だけである
Normally, this position is left unfilled,
通常 この相国は空席であったが
but by wielding the power of his faction, Lü Buwei was able to take the position for himself.
呂不韋は 一派の力を振るい
自ら その席に着いたのである
だが 政たちは この暴挙を
止めることは できなかった
But Zheng and the others could not put a stop to this.
（文官Ａ）クッ…
せっかく ここまで来ておいて！
He's finally made it this far...
With the power of the harem, it is no longer possible for us to resist the Lü Buwei camp.
（文官Ａ）後宮勢力によって―
もはや 我々には あらがえぬほど
呂不韋の陣営は…
（文官Ｂ）こうなっては
またイチから やり直すしか…
Do we have no choice but to start over from square one?
（政）ダメだ！
ここで食らいついていかねば―
No!
Unless we get our teeth into this now,
our chance for victory will be delayed once again.
我々の勝機は また先延ばしになる
No matter what it takes, we must keep pace with their power!
ここは 何が何でも
ヤツらの勢力に追随せねばならん！
But we no longer have any...
しかし 我々には もはや手だてが…
Your majesty?
（肆氏）大王さま？
Come with me.
（政）ついてこい
Th-This is...
こ… ここは…
（昌文君）まさか…
You don't mean...
My king!
（肆氏）大王さま！
Here I go.
行くぞ
Open the door.
開けろ
（兵士）ははっ！
Yes, your majesty!
久しぶりだな
It's been quite some time...
成蟜(せいきょう)！
Chengjiao!
Preview
Stage of Strategy
End